theplanetd.com 2019-04-05

# Privacy Policy

The Planet D believes very strongly in keeping your personal information confidential.  The following policy describes what information we collect and how it is used and shared.

 **Privacy Policy**

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their ‘Personally identifiable information’ (PII) is being used online. PII, as used in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

 **What personal information does The Planet D collect from the people that visit this blog, website or app?**

When ordering or registering on this site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address or other details to help you with your experience.

 **When is information collected?**

We collect information from you when you subscribe to a newsletter or email updates, leave a comment, make a purchase, respond to a survey, or otherwise enter information on this site.

 **How is this information used?**

We may use the information collected from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for a newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

  * To personalize a user's experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested.
  * To improve the website in order to better serve you.
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature.
  * To send periodic emails regarding the site or other products and services.

We will never sell or trade your information, and if at any time you want to unsubscribe from any email communication, you can do so by using the link at the bottom of each email.

 **How is visitor information protected?**

This website is scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit as safe as possible. We use regular Malware Scanning. We use an SSL certificate.

No personal information is stored on the site or its backend at any time.

 **Does this site use ‘cookies'?**

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your web browser (if you allow) that enables the site's or service provider's systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, a site may use cookies to help remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services.

We also use cookies to help compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

The Planet D mainly uses cookies to compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We also use trusted third party services that track this information, such as Google Analytics. (To learn exactly how Google uses your data in this case, please go here: [How Google uses data when you use our partners' sites or apps](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).)

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser settings.

 **Third party links**

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on this website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. The Planet D, therefore, has no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of this site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

 **Contacting us**

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy, you may contact us at theplanetd [at] gmail [dot] com.

 **Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes:**

  * On our Privacy Policy Page

 **Users are able to change their personal information:**

  * By Emailing Us

 **Opting Out**

If The Planet D chooses to send out newsletter updates in the future and we have your email address on file, you may receive a copy of our newsletter.  However, at the bottom of every newsletter will be an easy way to opt-out.  The editors of our site hate SPAM as much as you and have no intention of filling up e-mail boxes with unwanted messages.

 **Third Party Advertising**

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit networkadvertising.org.

 **Affiliate links**

In some instances, we may include affiliate links in posts where we recommend specific gear, tours, or activities. If you purchase something through one of our affiliate links, we receive a small commission at no extra cost to you. These links are always disclosed.

Among other programs, The Planet D is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for us to earn fees by linking to Amazon.com and affiliated sites.

 **Advertising Privacy Statement**

This Site is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site.  AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behavior on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies.  

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third-party partners. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative's multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).  However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.  

For European Economic Area Residents

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing.  If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact us at theplanetd [at] gmail [dot] com.or contact AdThrive at info@adthrive.com. If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences link at the bottom of the site. (Available in the EU.)
